<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technical Conference on IEvangelist</title>
    <link>http://davidpine.net/categories/technical-conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technical Conference on IEvangelist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://davidpine.net/categories/technical-conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey of a Lifetime</title>
      <link>http://davidpine.net/blog/journey-of-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidpine.net/blog/journey-of-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;style&gt;
    .iframe_container {
        position: relative;
        padding-bottom: 56.25%; /* 16:9 - this is responsive by adjusting the hight according to the width! */
        padding-top: 25px;
        height: 0;
    }
    .iframe_container iframe {
        position: absolute;
        top: 0;
        left: 0;
        width: 100%;
        height: 100%;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am returning home from a long trip in Serbia for &lt;a href=&#34;https://itkonekt.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IT Konekt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This was literally a trip of a lifetime and I could not be more grateful for such an amazing opportunity. Serbia has such an incredible culture and powerful history. I have been overwhelmed by the care and attention to detail from the organizers of &lt;strong&gt;IT Konekt&lt;/strong&gt;. This was my first time ever leaving the United States of America and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect. I was really nervous but equally excited. This was more of a journey of epic proportions than it was a conference trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to publicly thank &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LadyNaggaga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Maria Naggaga &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of Microsoft for referring &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Milica_Radovic_&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Milica Radovic &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/milicanastasic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Milica Nastasic &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-linkedin-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to me. They were looking for someone from the U.S. to speak about C# and Maria suggested me. This is the such an honor and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more excited to represent the U.S. and C# for my first international speaking engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;belgrade:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;Belgrade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;april-13-2018:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;April 13, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our journey began in Belgrade – the capitol city of Serbia. I arrived on the same flight into Belgrade as &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jcleblanc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jonathan LeBlanc &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of Box. In true movie fashion, our driver was waiting for us holding our names at the arrival gate of the airport. This was a warm welcome and made me feel special. After a 35 minute Car:Go (European Uber) drive we arrived at our hotel and while I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much sleep on the plane, I had energy from both the adrenaline and excitement. Just as soon as I was settling into my room, it was time to part for the first of seemingly countless speaker dinners. We were hungry and ready to immerse ourselves in the Serbian culture. We had a traditional Serbian dinner after a celebratory shot (or three) of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rakia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rakija &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-wikipedia-w&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;serbian fruit brandy&amp;rdquo;. Now, if you&amp;rsquo;re like me you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t know what rakija was&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;warning&lt;/em&gt; it is very strong! They fed us like kings and queens, we were treated like royalty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/breaking-bread.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Breaking Bread&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/csswizardry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Harry Roberts &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; sat to my right - he was a blast. Him and I shared a lot of common thoughts about the developer community. I really enjoyed his company. I asked him if he was on &lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt; so that I could follow him - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-smile-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; yeah 58k+ followers. The food was great. The people of Serbia know how to do meat, I might get myself banned from the United States for saying this but it is true, &amp;ldquo;Serbia has the best bacon in the world!&amp;rdquo; After a long night, I returned to my hotel where I immediately fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;april-14-2018:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;April 14, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 8 AM, I then decided I would rest my eyes a little longer (suffering from jetlag) I opened them again around 11 AM. My talk was at 4, so I had plenty of time. It was conference day, I was prepared and looking forward to giving my talk. I believe that presenting on C# was an excellent choice – it is a universal language. The attendees really enjoyed it and were thoroughly engaged. The only time people had their phones out were for taking pictures of me or the slides. I was asked to take pictures with several attendees both before and after my talk. This was the first time this has ever happened to me and it made my day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to a great conference, Jonathan LeBlanc and I took a casual stroll through Belgrade. We ended up walking over 14 miles and visited the Belgrade fortress. Along the way we were asked to help someone lift an A/C unit up a shaky ladder onto a roof within a closed market.&lt;/p&gt;




    

    
    




    
    
        
    


    

    &lt;div class=&#34;box alt&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;row uniform&#34;&gt;
        
        
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;4u&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/market.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;Market&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;4u&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/helping-others.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;Helping Others&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;4u&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/back-market.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;Back Market&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No one was injured in the photographing of this event&amp;hellip;our walk continued with no more interruptions. We arrived at the Belgrade fortress and it was very interesting. We were able to walk all over it, in the moat, in tunnels and even on the walls. Once we made our way to the back of the fortress we found a hill with a view. Here is a great shot from the fortress walls overlooking where the rivers meet - it truly was a remarkable view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/belgrade.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beograd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While touring the fortress we stumbled upon a torture museum, Jonathan and I decided &amp;ldquo;why not&amp;rdquo;. After the first few exhibits we kept asking each other &amp;ldquo;what the hell were we thinking!&amp;rdquo; I was tempted to share some of the pictures from the torture museum but nope, I&amp;rsquo;ll spare you the pain. Once we were finished witnessing the horrors, we were spent&amp;hellip;we walked back to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;april-15-2018:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;April 15, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday was traveling day and we were driving to Niš. The core group of speakers got to know each other extremely well during the trip, and I consider them all personal friends now. We spent hours in a jumbo van traveling the country of Serbia over the course of a week - quite the adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/the-van.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Van&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;niš:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;Niš&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;april-16-2018:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;April 16, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-humble-giant-jovan-milic:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;The Humble Giant (Jovan Milic)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived in Niš, we were greeted by several hosts. One of them was &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jovan_Milic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jovan Milic &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-wikipedia-w&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m referring to him from now on as the &amp;ldquo;humble giant&amp;rdquo;. He is 21 years old and has already been nominated for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/peace/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nobel Peace Prize&lt;/a&gt; four times! He was first nominated at the age of 15, making him the second youngest person in history to have been nominated. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever looking for inspiration read his story, it will hopefully put things a little more into perspective. For me, I can relate very much to his story and appreciate all the things that he&amp;rsquo;s done to earn his place in the world now. The next time you want to complain about the things you take for granted, remember his story and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.findraoul.tk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;support his cause&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/jovan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jovan Milic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several life lessons that I live by - this is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt; Expect nothing, but be grateful for everything.
&lt;cite&gt;David Pine&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jovan and the other hosts treated us like celebrities. We had a walking tour of the Niš fortress and city center. After arming ourselves with some umbrellas we were ready to take on the light rain. My umbrella just so happened to be pink. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure the color of my umbrella is relevant for this story, but I felt inclined to share it. After strolling around the fortress and then making our way back towards the city center - we needed some caffeine. We enjoyed turkish coffee and dark beer, because why not both?! I recall this evening very well, this is the night that Håkon told us about the time he built a balsawood raft with a group of volunteers. The raft weighed over 20 tons, and the intended purpose was to set course from South America (Peru) and sail to Easter Island. Why, you might ask - as both Jon&amp;rsquo;s and I did&amp;hellip;we were intrigued, why on earth would anyone want to do this? Simply to prove a point that it could be done. It would prove that Easter Island could have been inhabited by the people of South America. This voyage took place in 2015-2016 and was the spot light of world-wide news, for more details checkout the &lt;a href=&#34;http://kontiki2.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wiumlie.no/img/2015/kontiki2.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the story from Håkon himself here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again we enjoyed a traditional Serbian dinner. There was more rakija and as luck would have it, traditional Serbian music was played/performed live&amp;hellip;with the livlihood from the rakija there was dancing and singing, and all around celebration. Such a joyous time!&lt;/p&gt;




    

    
    




    
    
        
    


    

    &lt;div class=&#34;box alt&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;row uniform&#34;&gt;
        
        
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;4u&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/singing.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;Singing&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;4u&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/sitting.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;Sitting&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;4u&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/dancing.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;Dancing&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h3 id=&#34;april-17-2018:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;April 17, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conference Day! The stage was set. The crowds were drawing near, anticipation was building. News crews, wait&amp;hellip;news crews? Yes, we were actually interviewed and made it on the Serbian national news - several times. This was yet another first for me. The media was interested about our take on the IT community in Serbia. They were curious about how the developers of Serbia rank up against the rest of the world. That is a hard question to answer, but one thing was consistent with all of our responses - we believe that any developer can change the world! When you take talent, an idea and hunger to build something incredible there is no limit to what you can achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;box alt&#34;&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;row uniform&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;6u&#34;&gt;
         &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/media-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jon G.&#34;&gt;
         &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;6u&#34;&gt;
         &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/media-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me&#34;&gt;
         &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;row uniform&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;6u&#34;&gt;
         &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/media-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jonathan&#34;&gt;
         &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;6u&#34;&gt;
         &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/media-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Håkon&#34;&gt;
         &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference talks were all really well received. The developer community seemed eager to ask questions after sessions. As a speaker, this is what makes it all worth while - the gratifying moment when you know that you&amp;rsquo;ve been able to help someone and that you&amp;rsquo;ve delivered value. After the conference we spent more time walking around Niš, this is when I learned that Håkon brought a drone. We took turns flying it and taking pictures of the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;novi-sad:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;Novi Sad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;april-18-2018:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;April 18, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday was another traveling day. Our jumbo van trip was scheduled to take roughly four hours. But before we left, we were asked to be part of a ceremony with the President of municipalities, the mayor of Niš. The press was there to capture the moment. It was incredible sharing ideas for shared working spaces and encouraging hackathons. Our hosts served as translators, communicating our ambitions and guidance. The mayor was so pleased that he presented Håkon with a special honor - a medallion of Constantine the Great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt; IT experts are visiting the municipalities of Crvena Krst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;iframe_container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5jCy7oHbDaE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after the ceremony we drove to Novi Sad. We arrived without a hitch, settling into our hotels. Followed by a city tour, which proved to be a spectacular site. Dinner was at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.terasa.rs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Terasa&lt;/a&gt;. This sits right on the Danube river and at the foot of the Novi Sad fortress. Håkon was able to capture some amazing footage with his drone&amp;hellip;the view was beautifully stunning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;iframe_container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rC4pvMA8Qsk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sremski-karlovci-danube-river:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;Sremski Karlovci &amp;amp; Danube River&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;april-19-2018:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;April 19, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 19th was a really relaxing day, we had a walking tour, lunch on the Danube river, followed by a wine tasting at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.muzejzivanovic.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Museum of Beekeeping and Wine Cellar Zivanovic&lt;/a&gt;. Again, Håkon let his drone capture some of the essence and scenery. This video starts well beyond the town center, working its way back towards where we had lunch on the river. Yes, that establishment in the distance is where Håkon is navigating his drone recording this clip. I am seriously trying to convince my wife to let me purchase one of these drones. If you want to buy it for yourself &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Mavic-Platinum-Quadcopter-Camera-Batteries/dp/B07871KXMP&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here is the link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;iframe_container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/h6qwzQ65Fh8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This footage is amazing, video quality up to 4k if you&amp;rsquo;re into that sort of thing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;april-20-2018:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;April 20, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final conference day! I was up first and immediately following my talk, I needed to catch a cab back to Belgrade to catch my flight back home. I was sent home with a parting gift from the founders. I love the thoughtfulness, and it is so true that it&amp;rsquo;s better than a notebook and a pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;box alt&#34;&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;row uniform&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;5u&#34;&gt;
         &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/gift.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gift&#34;&gt;
         &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;7u&#34;&gt;
         &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/gift-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Note&#34;&gt;
         &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was excited to be returning home. I know that I was missed by Lyric, Londyn, Lennyx (my three sons) and Jen (wife). I&amp;rsquo;m thankful to have had a safe trip and shared so many awesome experiences. For those interested in the conference itself, I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting videos and more photos as they are released. For my talk, see below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-new-in-c-the-talk:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s new in C# (The Talk)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;strong&gt;GitPitch&lt;/strong&gt; for a while now, and I love it. Kudos to David Russel (the creator). For more details on &lt;strong&gt;GitPitch&lt;/strong&gt; checkout the official website by following the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gitpitch.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2018/04/gitpitch.png&#34; style=&#34;width: 400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the link for my talk, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitpitch.com/ievangelist/csharp#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new in C#&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. This was the talk that I presented at all three &lt;strong&gt;IT Konekt&lt;/strong&gt; conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-thoughts:838041a67cf795f61b4ef717b1e62653&#34;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blessed to have made so many new friends on this journey. These people are inspiring, you should follow them as they are true leaders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon Galloway&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jongalloway/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-linkedin-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jongalloway&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jongalloway&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://weblogs.asp.net/jongalloway&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Executive Director &lt;a href=&#34;http://dotnetfoundation.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;.NET Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, ASP.NET MVC 3/4/5 Author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan LeBlanc&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jcleblanc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-linkedin-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jcleblanc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jcleblanc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jcleblanc.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Director of Developer Advocacy &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.box.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Box&lt;/a&gt;, Emmy Award Winner, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Håkon Wium Lie&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/howcome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-linkedin-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wiumlie&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wiumlie.no/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creator of CSS, former CTO of Opera, Kontiki Adventurer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Milica Radovic&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/milicaradovic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-linkedin-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Milica_Radovic_&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Founder, IT Konekt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/milicanastasic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Milica Nastasic&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-linkedin-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-Founder, IT Konekt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jovan Milic&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jovan-milic-68713973&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-linkedin-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JMiliic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4x Nobel Peace Prize Nominee, Founder of Find Raoul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to organize an amazing technical conference</title>
      <link>http://davidpine.net/blog/how-to-organize-an-amazing-tech-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidpine.net/blog/how-to-organize-an-amazing-tech-conf/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;story-time:63ba67321c591922a170805947a2568e&#34;&gt;Story Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my third year organizing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkedotnet.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MKE DOT NET&lt;/a&gt;, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been accumulating plenty of interesting stories. Last year I was fortunate enough to have convinced Scott Hanselman to be our keynote speaker. Yes, &amp;ldquo;the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shanselman&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; - arguably the worlds most influential person in the tech industry. I was his ride to and from the airport and the conversations we had actually led to several key changes. As a result &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkedotnet.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MKE DOT NET&lt;/a&gt; will be even better than ever before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt; Had I looked at the lineup of speakers prior to agreeing, I would have declined&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind immediately started racing with thoughts like &amp;ldquo;does he only want to speak with well-known speakers&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;is this too small of a conference for such a celebrity?&amp;rdquo;. None of these thoughts were the least bit accurate. In fact, the reason was simple &amp;ldquo;we were not inclusive enough&amp;rdquo;. Honestly this was something that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even think about. I was driving Scott to the hotel where he was going to stay. The hotel was also the place where the conference was to be held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidpine.net/img/2017/06/hanselman.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;One does not simply drop &amp;quot;Hanselman&amp;quot; off at the hotel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No&amp;hellip;he requested that I give him a guided tour. He wanted to see the room layouts, he wanted to test equipment, ensure lighting, sound, connectivity, etc. We actually ended up reorganizing the entire layout of the keynote room as well as changing the number of projectors. His &amp;ldquo;perfectionist&amp;rdquo; side was shining through and it was really resonating with the team. Clearly he has done this a few more times than we have! &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-smile-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of his initial comments was hysterical:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt; This kind of looks and smells like grandmas house&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was referring to the decor of the hotel (very 60&amp;rsquo;s) and that the halls had a stale scent of mildew (the hotel has a water-park in it). Having just taken a sip of water, I nearly spit it out of my mouth in laughter - finally someone said what we had all been thinking! This resulted in a change of venue for 2017 and years to come. We&amp;rsquo;ll be at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paysbig.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Potawatomi Hotel &amp;amp; Casino&lt;/a&gt; this year. The new joke is obviously that it will now smell like cigarette smoke instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inclusion:63ba67321c591922a170805947a2568e&#34;&gt;Inclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth was simple. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkedotnet.com/2016/speakers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MKE DOT NET 2016&lt;/a&gt; only had one woman speaker and ironically she was speaking about Diversity. We were ready to lick our wounds and rise above it. I&amp;rsquo;m so proud to be part of this change and happy to communicate that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkedotnet.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MKE DOT NET&lt;/a&gt; now takes an active approach to ensure a more diverse speaker lineup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we started leveraging &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.papercall.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PaperCall.io&lt;/a&gt; as our event management system. It allowed us to make the speaker voting anonymized - but you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering how that helps with diversity. It actually doesn&amp;rsquo;t and that would be naive to assume so. What we did was invite &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AshleyPQPQP&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ashley Powell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/samsaha1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Samrat Saha&lt;/a&gt; (both MKE DOT NET speaker alumni) to join our technical committee. We loved that they were both eager to help and happily joined the team. They both have been a major part of the entire process and helped with the CFP outreach efforts. We believe this led to more submissions from their networks, ultimately leading to a more inclusive speaker lineup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 24 sessions and including the keynote, we are proud to have eight women speakers this year! If you&amp;rsquo;re a numbers person - that is an &lt;strong&gt;800% increase&lt;/strong&gt; year-over-year and we plan on doing even better as we evolve. We are actively making our conference as inclusive as possible - and we celebrate the communities participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolution:63ba67321c591922a170805947a2568e&#34;&gt;Evolution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are only going to grow and learn and become a better more cohesive unit as time marches forward. We are evolving! The people who make up the team are so passionate about bringing forth their visions for a better Midwest technical community. But that isn&amp;rsquo;t without conflict or disagreement. In fact our team is great at hashing things out. Not every idea is the best! Knowing how to work together and encouraging ideas is key. We foster an environment which breeds creativity but also bases our direction on results. The team shares a vision and we strive to make that vision obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community:63ba67321c591922a170805947a2568e&#34;&gt;Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course none of this would be possible without our strong community. I&amp;rsquo;m proud to play my part and contribute what I can, and I&amp;rsquo;m humbled to be immersed in such a rich pool of technical knowledge and passion. It is inspiring to see the things we&amp;rsquo;re doing and even more so to be involved! Often the hallways of a technical conference are the stomping grounds for some of the best bits of conversation. In my regional speaking engagements this year I&amp;rsquo;m hearing just how amazing we are in the Midwest time and time again. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for all of these awesome success stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tools:63ba67321c591922a170805947a2568e&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being that the entire team cannot always be in the same place at the same time - it is vital to leverage tools that allow everyone on the team to work together. This will serve as a simple listing of some of things that we have used along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.papercall.io/mkedotnet2017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PaperCall.io - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-paper-plane&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for CFP and speaker selection process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/mke-dot-net-2017-tickets-32702277392&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eventbrite - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-calendar&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for event ticketing/sales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Docs/Sheets/Forms - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-google&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for internal documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stickies.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stickies.io - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-sticky-note&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for organizing schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trello Boards - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-trello&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for organizing ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zoom.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zoom.us - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-video-camera&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for video conferencing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adobe.com/products/illustrator.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Adobe Illustrator - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-pencil-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; designing logos, creating illustrations and icons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Adobe Photoshop - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-picture-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; art directing photos, creating images, correcting color&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mkedotnet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for social networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A word on the website, we use for source control &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github-square&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and it is actually a static website. It uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://harpjs.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HarpJs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which sits atop &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NodeJs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Updates are seamless and fast with &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code - &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-code-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-story:63ba67321c591922a170805947a2568e&#34;&gt;Closing Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke at &lt;a href=&#34;https://indycode.amegala.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Indy.Code()&lt;/a&gt; in Indianapolis back in March, 2017. It was a great experience and the folks over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amegala.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amegala&lt;/a&gt; really know how to organize a technical conference! Anyways, prior to one of my talks I was asking the crowd a little about technical conferences in Indianapolis. I was told that &lt;a href=&#34;https://indycode.amegala.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Indy.Code()&lt;/a&gt; was the first major conference in seven years. When I asked them what they do to fill that void, three of them immediately shouted out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt; We travel to Milwaukee, WI in the fall for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkedotnet.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MKE DOT NET&lt;/a&gt; - it&amp;rsquo;s a technical conference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a small world, hey! They were extremely excited to learn my role&amp;hellip;and I too shared in their excitement. For in that moment I knew that all the hard work was paying off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thank-you:63ba67321c591922a170805947a2568e&#34;&gt;Thank you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sincere thank you is in order for everyone who makes this possible. Thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LadyNaggaga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Maria Naggaga&lt;/a&gt; for not only being willing to speak at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkedotnet.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MKE DOT NET&lt;/a&gt;, but responding to my ask within minutes - stating that she would be honored! Thank you to the community, the speakers, those who submit who don&amp;rsquo;t get to speak, those of you who attend. Thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centare.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Centare&lt;/a&gt; for supporting all these efforts year-after-year and the investment back into the community. Thank you to all the sub-committees of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkedotnet.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MKE DOT NET&lt;/a&gt; that give their brilliance and support taking on tasks like, marketing, driving attendance, seeking sponsorship, creating and maintaining the website, deciding on scheduling, venue, meals, logistics, all the countless planning efforts - thank you. Anyone else that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of, thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>